Hey everyone, in this video, we'll be exploring
the Litho NFT market place.
Litho is a digital asset marketplace for the
CENNZnet blockchain. You can use Litho to
mint your own nfts, add title, description
and other meta data. You can even set a percentage
of royalty you would gain from each sale of
the NFT.
In this video we'll be
Setting up the CENNZnet browser extension,
Creating a CENNZnet wallet and finally minting
a NFT using the Litho marketplace.
To install the browser extension, go to the
link provided in the description, Click add
to chrome and select Add Extension. Once it's
added you'll get a notification. YOu can pin
the extension for easy access.
Now that we have the extension added, let's
create an account. Click on the extension
and click the plus icon. A mnemonic seed will
be generated. Store this securely and do not
share this with anyone. Once done click on
next step. Here you can set a name for your
wallet, and a password to verify you before
each transaction. Go ahead and fill this up
and click Add account. Now your account is
created.
Now let's go to the litho marketplace. The
link will be in the description. Click on
connect wallet and select your wallet. You
will be asked to update the metadata so do
that. Once done your account is linked. Now
click on the create button or mint NFt. Here
you will be asked for a title, description
and number of copies of the nft. You can edit
advanced options as well. These are optional.
Here you can set up royalty percent, which
defines a percent cut from each sale of the
token and add attributes, which m. Once you've
filled it, you can click next to upload the
asset. Here select Choose from folder and
select the asset you want to upload. You can
choose the content storage if applicable.
It defaults to IPFS. Once done click on preview
to view preview of your nft. Once you've finalized,
you can click on mint to create it. It will
take some time to upload the assets. Once
it's uploaded, you'll be prompted to authorize
2 transactions, the first one is to create
a collection and the second is to mint the
nft. Enter your password and approve it. once
done You'll get a conformation that your NFT
is created successfully. To view your NFTs,
click on the top right button showing your
wallet and then click my profile. here you
can see all of your NFTs. On clicking it,
you can view the details of the NFT. here
you can view the ipfs link and ipfs meta data.
To view the transaction you can head over
to [https://uncoverexplorer.com/] Select your
network and fill your wallet address here
you can see your transactions.